《越狱》前情回顾
Previously on Prison Break
我没有杀他 迈克尔
I didn't kill that man. Michael
如果你没有杀特伦斯 斯蒂德曼
If you didn't kill Terrence Steadman,
究竟是谁要陷害你?
how the hell did someone make it look like you did?
我会救你出去的
I'm getting you out of here.
不可能   除非监狱是你设计的
That's impossible. Not if you designed the place,it isn't.
最好是开着的
Better be open,bro.
你要我触犯法律
You're asking me to break the law.
我只是让你犯个小错误
I'm asking you to make a mistake
忘记锁门就行了
forget to lock up.
我们进去了
We're in.
谁杀了特伦斯 斯蒂德曼?
Who killed Terrence Steadman?
没人
Nobody.
特伦斯 斯蒂德曼还活着
Terrence Steadman's still alive
你好  特伦斯
Hello,Terrence.
快拉警报
Sound the alarm!
发生什么事了?
What's going on?
不! 不要!
No! No!
我们现在怎么办?
What do we do now?
跑
We run
那些逃犯是谁?
The escapees,who were they?
这里有份名单
Got a list right here.
念给我听
Read it to me,if you could.
迈克尔 斯科菲尔德 建筑工程师
Michael Scofield,structural engineer,
因持枪抢劫被判5年
five years for armed robbery
本杰明 迈尔斯 富兰克林
Benjamin Miles Franklin,
退役军人
former U.S. Army
因非法所得失窃赃物被判8年
eight years for possession of stolen goods
约翰 阿布鲁奇
John Abruzzi
同名黑帮组织老大
don of the crime family of the same name
因策划谋杀终生监禁
Life without parole for conspiracy to commit murder.
查尔斯 帕托塞克
Charles "Haywire" Patoshik
因二级谋杀判60年
60 years for second-degree murder
费尔南多 苏克雷
Fernando Sucre
因暴力抢劫被判5年
five years for aggravated robbery
大卫 阿克斯
David "Tweener" Apolskis
因特大盗窃罪判5年
five years for grand larceny
西奥多 帝博格
Theodore "T-Bag" Bagwell
因六起绑架 强奸案及 一级谋杀罪判终身监禁
life for six counts  of kidnapping,rape and first-degree murder
还有林肯 布伦斯
And Lincoln Burrows
原计划下周执行死刑
scheduled to die next week
罪名是谋杀莱娜斯总统的哥哥
for the murder of President Reynold's brother.
他们越狱多久了?
How long has it been since they got over the wall?
昨晚八点逃跑的
8:00 last night
斯科菲尔德和布伦斯是亲兄弟
Scofield-- he and Burrows were brothers.
没错
That's right.
斯科菲尔德就是整个越狱计划的主谋
And he's the mastermin of this whole thing
他们是这么说的
That's what they're saying
我要有关他的所有信息
I want everything they've got on him.
他们在哪里?
Where are they?
什么声音?
What the hell is that?
我们走
Let's go.
我们必须想办法到对面去    你说什么？
All we got to do is make it to the other side. What?
想法子到对面去
Make it to the other side.
快点 跑起来
Come on,guys
再快点
Pick it up
火车加速了!
The thing is gaining speed,man!
太快了!
It's going too fast!
穿过去!
Go through
什么?  穿过去!
What?  Go through!
快!
Go!
站住!别动!
Freeze!
斯科菲尔德  我会开枪的
I will gun you down,Scofield!
直升机还有其他人在哪?
Where's the aerial and the others?
他们返回加油了
They're back on the ground refueling.
这帮畜生
Son of a bitch.
先生
Sir
记者们都到场了
Media's ready.
我想谈一下谋杀林肯总统的凶犯 约翰 威尔克斯 布斯
I'd like to,uh,talk about John Wilkes Booth for a moment if I could,Abraham Lincoln's killer
总共费时12天把他抓捕归案
12 days,that's how long it took to find him.
他在逃期间的日记中写道
In his journal during this period,he wrote
影子左右为伴 夜幕我来主宰
that the shadow was his friend,the night his domain.
他承认不管犯罪时的精神状态如何
He acknowledged that whatever neuroses drove the criminal
精神问题会由于逃跑和追捕进一步恶化
to commit the original crime is compounded,magnified by flight,by the sounds of dogs at his heels.
恐惧变成了妄想
Fear becomes paranoia,
妄想最终变为精神错乱
paranoia ultimately psychosis.
我在这里提这件事是因为
I bring this up,because,in 140 years,
140年以来 逃犯的基本心理没有改变过
the fundamental mind of the escaped man has not changed.
逃犯也是人
The escaped man is still human.
他们也会害怕
He is still afraid,
他们不惜一切要逃脱追捕
and he will stop at nothing in his attempt at flight.
所幸的是
Fortunately for us
尽管我们的追捕尚未有突破 夜色也站在他们一边
while our quarry has shadow and night as his ally
我们还有样更厉害的法宝:电视
we have something far greater: television.
我想动员所有正在收看节目的人
I would encourage everyone who is watching,
这个国家的每个人
everyone in this country
好好看看这些脸
to take a good look at these faces.
就是这些人
These men right here
现在是美国头八号通缉犯
are now the eight-most-wanted men in America.
我以为我们都计划好了
I thought I thought this out.
怎么会被他们追得这么惨?
You saw all those guys back there?
关键就是他们只能在后面追
The key is they're back there,
而我们快他们一步
and we're up here.
这个样子还要持续多久?
Yeah,and how long is that going to last?
特别是我们连小便都要憋着
Yeah,especially since we don't have a pot to piss in
这都要归功于阿布鲁奇神奇消失的飞机
thanks to Abruzzi's magically disappearing jet.
反正你本来就上不了那架飞机
Hey,you were never going to be on that plane,brother.
不要以为我不知道你要去哪 斯科菲尔德
And don't think I don't know where you were going either,Scofield.
我要去哪?
Where am I going?
我不知道
Oh,I don't know.
犹他州?
Utah?
你打算何时给我们说说钱的事情?
When were you planning on telling us about the money,man?
什么钱?
What money?
韦斯特莫兰德藏的500万美元
$5 million that Westmoreland planted
在犹他州的沙漠里
in the desert in Utah.
不知道你在说什么
You don't know what you're talking about.
是你希望我不知道吧
You wish I didn't know.
等等 等等 什么钱?
Wait,wait. What money?
狱长?
Warden?
FBI介入得早了些 你认为呢?
It's a little early for the FBI to be showing up,don't you think?
听着 我明白
Look,I get it.
现在还是由你主导调查
It's still your investigation,
但是一旦逃犯越过州界线
but once those criminals cross state lines,
那就由联邦政府来处理了
it'll become a federal matter.
没错  不会出现这种情况的
Yeah,well,that is not going to happen.
但愿你是对的
I hope you're right.
那就是为什么我提议
That's why I was going to suggest that we cut
不要让部门间的政策碍手碍脚
through any interagency politics from the outset.
完全透明
Full transparency.
那当然
Absolutely.
很好
Good.
或许你能和我说说有关唐克雷蒂医生的事
Then maybe you can tell me about Dr. Tancredi.
没什么好说的
There's nothing to tell.
从我掌握的情况来看 她或许也参与了这次逃跑计划
From what I'm hearing,she may have abetted the escapees
门不上锁 默许他们跑出去
opened the door that allowed them to get out.
正如我刚才所说的 没什么好说的
Like I said,there's nothing to tell.
你可不太不透明 狱长
You're not being very transparent,Warden.
听着 我不想讨论我的手下
Look,I don't discuss my staff.
或许你应该这么做
Maybe you should,
因为她可能是整个事情的关键
because she may be the key to this thing.
我们需要和她谈谈
We need to speak with her.
就是现在 马宏先生
Right now. Mr. Mahone,
她现在不想和任何人说话
she's not going to be speaking with anyone.
情况怎么样?
How are we doing?
她现在正在输液
Well,the IVs are hydrating her.
我们给她注射了解毒剂 每小时半毫克
We got her on a naloxone infusion,half milligram per hour.
你觉得存活下来的几率多大?
What do you think the chances are?
我们已经尽力了
Well,we've done everything on our end.
现在完全取决于她自身了
It's really up to her.
求生意志强就可以活下去
Either she fights and lives,or she quits and dies.
你想干什么...
Hey! What do you think...
你要什么就拿去
Do whatever thing you got to do,man.
孩子... 如果你敢报警
boy... you call the cops,
我就把这个戳进你的眼睛
I will put this thing right here......in your eye.
谢谢
Thank you.
建筑工程师?
Structural engineer,huh?
和平常的不一样 这么多纹身
Not the kind, you'd expect to get that much ink.
绝对与众不同
Not the kind at all.
你觉得要纹成这样需要花多久?
How long do you think it'd take to get something like that?
几百小时吧... 200小时
Hundred hours... 200.
给他纹身的刺青师 一定和他接触时间很久
Tattoo artist who gave it to him must have spent a lot of time on him then.
我去把这个人找出来
I'll find out who it was.
贝利克先生
Mr. Bellick.
不要和我说话
Don't talk to me.
没问题 但这样不好合作
Fine,but it's going to make collaboration kind of hard.
合作？
Collaboration?
我带队冒着艰险搜寻 而你在开新闻发布会
I got men out here in harm's way, and you're giving press conferences.
媒体不过是种工具
The press is a tool.
我会比你更快把逃犯抓回来
I'll bring those men back quicker than bloodhounds will.
我们不需要你
We don't need you.
我们紧跟逃犯遗留的线索
We're hot on these guys' trail,
追踪到他们不过是时间问题
and it's just a matter of time till we nail them.
追踪遗留线索的最大问题是
The problem I find with being on a trail
你们总是晚他们一步
is that by definition you'll always be behind your prey.
等着瞧吧
We'll see about that.
我没有武器
I'm not armed.
你必须要原谅我
You'll have to excuse me
在这个当口上  我不太信任人
if I'm a little short on trust at the moment.
小姐 我向你保证
I assure you,young woman,
我是最不具威胁的人物
I'm the furthest thing from a threat.
我想我用止痛剂已经能证明这点了
I think the Percocet pretty much ensures that.
很好 那么你不会介意我拍张照
Good,then you won't mind if I capture this moment
为了子孙后代
for posterity.
这么做对你没有任何好处
Won't do you any good.
你对有人因为谋杀你而马上要被执行死刑 无动于衷
You don't care that someone's going to be executed for your murder
依然端坐于此
while you're just sitting here.
我不是那个挑选林肯 布伦斯 作为替死鬼的人
I'm not the one choose Lincoln Burrows as the fall guy.
那是谁干的? 你那个总统妹妹?
Who did? Your sister,the president?
你不会明白的
You don't understand.
对于这一切 我就是个囚犯
I'm a prisoner to all of this.
算了吧
Oh,come on.
你可以站出来
You could have come forward.
你甚至可以在事情发生之前就出手阻止它
You could have stopped this thing before it even got started.
不 我真的被囚禁了
No,I really am a prisoner.
现在你也是了
And now,you are,too.
从你关上门那一刻开始
The moment you let that door shut behind you.
你有没有感到惊讶过
Didn't it strike you as curious
为什么外面一个保安都没有
that there wasn't any security out there?
这扇门只能从外面打开
The doors only open from the outside.
玻璃有两英寸这么厚 还是防弹的
The glass is two inches thick,bulletproof.
进了这里就出不去了
There's no getting out of here,young woman.
我们现在必须甩掉他们
We got to dump them now.
不行
Can't.
他们知道犹他的事情了
They know about Utah.
更重要的原因是
All the more reason to dump them.
一旦他们被抓
If they get caught,
他们定会招供我们的去向
they feds will know exactly where we're going.
我们去告诉他们
We'll tell them.
我们需要保证他们别惹事
We just got to make sure they stay afloat
等我们到了犹他州就分道扬镳
until we're off in Utah,doing what we got to do.
你真的认为钱会藏在那儿?
You really think the money's going to be there?
查尔斯平时可能真话不多
Charles might have had a flexible relationship
但人之将死... 他没有理由再撒谎了
with the truth,but at the end...at the end,there'd be no reason for him to lie about it.
我计划一旦拿到钱 就逃到墨西哥
I figure once we bag it,we cross over into Mexico,
然后搭乘颠簸的破烂巴士
take a whole bunch of bumpy second-class bus rides
直到我们抵达巴拿马
till we hit Panama.
你还真计划了开潜水店的事情了?
You really got a fix on this dive shop thing,huh?
目前来说 在接下去的10或20年中
Right now,I wouldn't mind swinging in a hammock
有吊床睡就不错了
for the next ten or 20 years.
全国上下都在搜捕我们
We got half the country after us.
如果没有帮助的话
We ain't making it to Panama or Utah.
我们去不了巴拿马或犹他州
Not without help.
维罗妮卡帮不了我们
Veronica can't help us.
你怎么能这么说?
How can you say that?
我们没有钱 衣服...
We don't have money,clothes...
我早就安排好一切了
I already got all that.
我还以为整个计划就是阿布鲁奇的飞机   阿布鲁奇的飞机是A计划
I thought the plan was Abruzzi's jet. Abruzzi's jet was Plan A.
这么说我们还有...
Then we got...
我们所需要的一切
Everything we need.
在哪？
Where?
仓库里
Storage.
斯科菲尔德设计了这个纹身而不是你?
Scofield designed the tattoo,not you?
他把整个纹身都设计好了
He brought the entire thing in,
每个细节
every element.
比如说这个 奇怪的西斯廷教堂
I mean,look at it,it's the freakin' Sistine Chapel.
我知道这家伙是个工程师之类的
I knew the guy was an engineer or whatever,
但是看看他在艺术上的造诣简直难以置信
but man,his skill as an artist was unbelievable.
还有什么? 你能告诉我他这个人的性情吗?
What else? What can you tell me about him as a person?
他很酷
Uh,he was cool,you know.
但是凡事都对细节要求苛刻
But talk about a detail nazi.
是个完美主义者
Everything had to be perfect,
要求纹的与他画的一模一样
exactly as he drew it.
我一直对这件事有种异样的感觉
I always sort of had the feeling that the whole thing
整件事别有内情
was some sort of inside joke
只有他自己清楚
that only he was in on.
我们有你的电话号码对吗?
We have your number,right?
对
Yeah.
我会再和你联系的 谢谢
I may be calling you. Thank you.
福蕾!
Foley!
那条长马路叫什么名字?
What was the name of that long road
就是那条我们去监狱路过的?
we took to get to the prison?
English Boulevard.
还有出来后的那条呢
And out in front of the prison,
两条路在那里有交错
the two streets that intersect with it?
Fitz和Percy 为什么问这个？
Fitz and Percy. Why?
谢谢
Thank you.
准备出发   我们去哪?
Saddle up. Where we going?
去一个不用再当乡下人
Somewhere where we can stop being cons
可以光明正大做普通人的地方
and start being civilians.
你为什么不把所有的谜团都直接告诉我们呢?
You know,why don't you cut out all the riddles,Snowflake,and just give it to us straight.
怎么了?
What?
小孩
little one.
你们在干吗?
What are you doing?
那个 呃...
Well,uh...
我们在钓鱼
We're just fishing.
不用鱼杆吗?
With no poles?
我们喜欢用手抓鱼
Well,we like to fish with our hands.
对...
Yes,eh...
手抓鱼
hand-fishing.
我正想问问你
I think the question is,
你在这里干什么?
What are you doing out here?
打猎     格雷西?
Hunting.  Gracie?
格雷西快跑
Gracie,get away.
你们是那些福克斯河监狱的逃犯
You're those guys from Fox River.
别动 一步也不要动
Don't, don't any of you move a freakin' muscle.
从她边上滚开!
Get away from her!
好...别激动 冷静
ay,okay,just.. relax,relax.
呆在原地别动
You stay where you are.
把枪放下
Drop the gun!
把小女孩放下 约翰
John,put the girl down.
扔掉枪
Put the gun down.
把枪放下
Drop the gun!
马上扔掉枪
Put down the gun,John.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
一
One.
我要开枪了
I'll pull the trigger.
二!
Two!
好孩子
Good boy.
拿起枪
Get the gun.
捡起来
Pick it up!
不要伤害她 不要...
Don't you hurt her,don't you...
你会没事的
You're going to be all right.
跑回你爸爸那
Run to Daddy.
我不会对任何人说任何事
I ain't going to say anything,to anybody,man.
你的车在哪?
Where's your car?
在路边
Up on the road.
钥匙呢
Keys.
你被认为是从犯
You're being considered an accessory to this;
你知道吗?
you know that,don't you?
我现在所知甚少
I know very little right now.
你打开了医务室的门
You opened the door to the infirmary
让斯科菲尔德从那逃跑
that allowed Scofield to escape,
是你干得吗?
didn't you?
不是
No.
你有没有和斯科菲尔德发生过性关系?
Did you have a sexual relationship with Scofield?
没有
No.
但是你对他有感觉
But you had feelings for him.
还有其他7个人也跑出去了
Seven other men got out,you know.
谁?
Who?
抱歉先生
Oh,I am sorry,sir.
今天周六 我们不营业
It's Saturday; we're not open.
要的就是不营业
Well,that's sort of the point.
怎么了 先生?
Sorry,sir?
看到吗 我需要你动手术
See,I'm going to need some work done,
而且我需要秘密手术
and I'm going to need it done privately.
抱歉 你刚才说你需要动手术?
I'm sorry,you said you needed the work done?
这里不是医疗诊所吗?
This is a medical clinic,isn't it?
当然是 不过是给动物看病的
Well,of course it is,sir,but for animals.
你怎么伤成这样?
Oh,man,what happened to you?
你需要去医院
You need medical attention.
坚持住
Sir,listen... Hold up.
我帮你去喊救护车
I'm going to get an ambulance.
在这谁都不许打电话 明白吗  医生?
Nobody's going to be doing any calling here,Doctor.
听你的
Fine.
你想要什么?
Wh-What do you want?
真不敢相信
我想那个没良心的东西滚下车
That's it. I want Eye-Tie out of the car right now,man.
那还是个小女孩呀
That was a little girl!
你们难道没有良心?
Don't you have a heart?
上帝
God!
我也有女儿
I have a daughter.
我也有个小女孩
I have a little girl!
我也有一个
I got one,too.
但是如果我不那么干的话
But if I hadn't done what I had to do,
我们以后就看不到他们了 不是吗?
we wouldn't be on our way to see'em right now,would we?
在那右转弯
Turn right up there.
等等 我们去哪?
Hold on. Where we going?
奥斯威戈
Oswego.
那是西边
That's west,man.
我们要往东边赶
We need to go east.
我家在芝加哥
My family's back in Chicago.
你认为警察会不知道么?
And you think the cops don't know about it?
你不认为他们正在你家坐等着你自投罗网吗?
You think they're not just sitting there,waiting for you to come running back home?
你有毛病吧?
What's the matter with you?
那去纽约如何?
Well,what about New York?
怎么样?
What about it?
我老婆怀孕了
My girl's pregnant,bro.
他们肯定知道你的弱点
Understand your love is your weakness right now,
就是你的爱情
and they know about it.
那不意味着你必须放弃爱情
Doesn't mean it has to stop you.
应该在这方面学的聪明点
You just got to be smart about it.
去奥斯威戈
Get to Oswego.
奥斯威戈不在那个方向
Oswego was not on the way,Snowflake.
问题不是奥斯威戈在哪
It's not where Oswego is.
问题是奥斯威戈有什么
It's what's in Oswego.
队长 斯科菲尔德的信用卡记录显示
Captain,Scofield's credit card transaction history.
他入狱前曾在威尔郡花了一大笔钱
Spent a lot of money here in Will County  before he was incarcerated
正是 他是芝加哥来的
Exactly. He was from Chicago.
为什么一个芝加哥人会远道而来
Why does a guy from Chicago come all the way out here
在短短一个月内在这里花上八千块钱
and spend north of eight grand in all these places in little over a month?
洗车 语音邮件 保管费 租车...
Car wash,voice mail,storage,car rental...
我们已经派人去查了   很好
We got guys looking into it. Good.
队长  联邦调查局的人怎么办? 我们要通知他们么?
Hey,Captain,what about the Feds? Should we tell them?
你说呢? 贝利克队长
What do you think? Captain Bellick?  Captain Bellick
我们有了些新信息
We got something.
树林那边的猎人说 刚刚遇到了逃犯中的五个人
Hunter up by Tamarack just ran into five of the cons.
斯科菲尔德就住这儿?
So this is where Scofield lived?
是的  直到2个月被捕前 他一直住在这
Yeah,up until about two months ago when he was incarcerated.
母亲去世了 父亲不知所踪
Mother's dead,father's a deadbeat.
这个世界除了你哥哥 你一无所有
You got nothing in the whole world but your brother.
所以你先是计划
So you plan.
然后又准备了几个月
And you scheme for months...
直到理出头绪
...till you get it right.
万事俱备
Every single element
然后你销毁所有证据
And then you destroy all the evidence.
派潜水员到河里看看
I want divers down in the river.
你手机不会有信号的
You won't get cell coverage.
我们在一片荒地中间
We're in the middle of nowhere.
西蒙大拿这附近
Digital carriers don't have cell towers way out here
没有信号塔
in Western Montana.
闭嘴吧  特伦斯
How about shutting up,Terrence?
帮你省点力气罢了
Just trying to save you some effort.
他们像一张网一样  这些人
They're like a web,these people.
你越反抗情况就越糟糕
The harder you struggle,the worse it gets.
怎么听起来像个懦夫 在为自己找借口
Sounds to me like a coward trying to justify himself.
如果我不坏他们的事 什么都不说  我就能活
If I stay out of the way and stay quiet,I stay alive.
他们这么告诉我的
That's what they said; that's what they told me.
你愿意就这么活着么?
And you're willing to live like this,
活在一个密封的盒子里面
in a hermetically-sealed box
看着外面变得一团糟 我得保护自己
while everything out there goes to hell? Self-preservation is a strong motivator.
真相也应得到保护
So is the truth.
别这么做
Don't.
小姐
Young woman?
别这么做
Don't.
你怎么样  伙计?
How you doing,buddy?
我吓坏了  就这样
I'm pretty freaked out,that's how I'm doing.
他们抢了你的车  对吧?
They took your car,didn't they?
78年的大切罗基
1978 Grand Cherokee.
对  他们往那边去了?
Yeah. Which way did they go?
往北通奥斯威戈的那条路
Up that way north toward Oswego.
奥斯威戈  抱歉离开一下
Oswego. Pardon me.
把斯科菲尔德的文件拿来  吉米
Scofield's paperwork-- get it,Jimmy.
就是那些信用卡记录
The credit card stuff.
在这儿  队长
Right here,Captain.
当然了
Of course.
他会把他需要的东西藏哪里呢?
Where is he going to put all the crap you need to disappear?
我们到奥斯威戈去  伙计们
We're going to Oswego,  boys.
有人来看你了
You have a visitor.
谢谢
Thank you.
Thanks.
你失望了
You look disappointed.
没有 我以为我父亲会来
No. I thought you were going to be my father.
他打电话给你了吗?
You heard from him?
他办公室的人打过
His office.
给你带了些换的衣服
Well,brought you a change of clothes.
我猜你可能需要...
Figured,you know...
谢谢
Thanks.
还有你的包
And your purse.
你把它忘在医务室了
You left it in the infirmary.
我猜我这回麻烦大了
I'm in a lot of trouble,I think.
我...
I,um...
我得向你道歉
I need to apologize to you.
他们用我的工作威胁我 如果我不说...
They threatened my job if I didn't talk,and...
不怪你...
No,no,no,no. No.
人人都该知道
One thing you learn when you're walking the steps
不要把自己的过错怪在别人身上
is that you never outsource a blame that belongs in your own backyard.
好吧
Well,
在监狱工作的人里
you're not the first correctional worker
你不是第一个对犯人有感觉的人
that fell for a con,
相信我
trust me.
他从来也不在乎
He never cared.
一点也不
Not one bit.
你想什么呢?
What are you thinking about?
犯过的错
Mistakes.
你也没有选择
You had to do it.
我不该
Not like I did.
我毁了她的生活
I ruined her life.
你现在没什么办法了
Well,there's nothing you can do about it now.
不是的
That's not true.
你喜欢她?
You fell for her,huh?
奥斯威戈在哪?
Where's Oswego?
可能还有半里
Half mile maybe.
好
Good.
你要怎么办?  特伦斯 开枪么?
What are you going to do,Terrence,shoot me?
把我的内脏崩的满屋子都是? 然后呢?
Blow my guts all over this house? Then what?
你走不了  对吧?
You can't leave,remember?
你杀了我 也得跟我绑一块
You kill me,you're stuck with me.
在这我是安全的
I'm safe here.
在这你是个囚犯
You're a prisoner here.
可我还活着
But I'm still breathing.
可是我要是出去了... 哪怕只一步
If I go outside... one step,
就难说了
I won't be.
你这么看我... 觉得我像个魔鬼
You look at me... like I'm the devil.
我放弃了我的家庭
I gave up my family.
我的牙
My teeth.
我每天吃止痛药
I eat Percocet all day
减缓我可悲生命的痛苦
just to dull the pain of my miserable existence.
你不知道我经历了什么
You have no idea what I've been through.
你经历了什么?
What you've been through?
这跟你没关系 特伦斯
别
Don't.
黑角警署
Blackfoot Sheriff's Department.
你好  我是维罗妮卡 多诺万
Hello. My name's Veronica Donovan.
我需要你尽快派一队人到 光明路尽头的房子来
I need you to send a unit to the house at the end of Light Road as soon as possible.
抱歉  女士 你是在报告一起罪案么?
I'm sorry,ma'am,but are you calling to report a crime?
是的
Yeah.
由美国总统犯下的
By the President of the United States.
派人来吧
Send the car.
抱歉先生 我想我做不了
I'm sorry,sir,I-I don't think I can do this.
这么多神经...
There are nerves...
你需要专家 不是么? 我不...
Look,you need a specialist,okay? I don't...
你--你需要
You-You need somebody
知道该怎么做的人
who knows what they're doing.
我现在没那福气  大夫
I don't have the luxury of choice here,Doctor.
我的手已经在那箱子里几个小时了 就要废了
My hand has been in that box for hours now. It is dying.
先生  我做不了这个
Sir,I am not capable of doing this.
虽然我只有一只手 但我可以
I only have one hand,but I could
在你到那门口之前
stick this in your neck before
把这玩艺扎你脖子里
you get to that door.
如果这么说还不够
Now,if that's not incentive enough for you,
我知道你老婆叫古达特
I see that you have a Mrs. Gudat out there.
这样的名字
With a name like that
这样的小地方
in a county like this,
应该不难找吧?
old Mrs. Gudat would not be too hard to find now,would she?
好吧
Fine.
我什么也保证不了
I can promise you nothing.
我也是
Story of my life.
我得帮你躺下
I'll have to put you under.
你当我傻么?
Do I really look that stupid?
先生  没有麻药
Sir,I cannot do
我做不了手术
a procedure like this without an anesthetic.
我得把坏死的组织割掉
I have to cut away dead flesh.
没有普通人能不打麻药
Nobody can undergo a procedure like this
就接受这样的手术!
without an anesthetic!
我不是普通人
I ain't nobody.
施韦策是制作卫浴设备的公司
Schweitzer was the plumbing company that made the toilet
斯科菲尔德卸掉了马桶 从他的牢房里逃走
Scofield took off to get out of his cell.
螺丝钉就是工具
Allen bolt was the fitting.
全在这了  对吧?
It's all here,isn't it?
很让人惊讶
It's amazing.
Ripe Chance Woods.
附近有叫那个名字的地方么?
There a place in the vicinity with that name?
派人查查
Got someone looking into it.
狱方正在去奥斯威戈的一个仓库
DOC's moving on a storage facility in Oswego.
队长  经理说
Captain,manager says
斯科菲尔德在164单元有个租间
that Scofield's got a lease on unit 164.
现在仍然在用
It's still active.
我们在第八街  第三街  和小巷里 都有人
We got guys on 8th Street,3rd Street,then the alley.
如果他们到这来 肯定跑不了
If they're in there,Captain,we got'em boxed.
好好准备准备
We push right up the gut,then.
要是他们谁不听话
Any one of them makes a threatening move,
就毙了他
put a hole in 'em.
收到
You got it.
警官...
Officer...
这应该由我来解决 你待远点
This is my collar,smart guy. Back the hell off.
关上门
Close the door.
这里还没线索？
Still nothing on this place?
没 他们无功而返
Nope. They're coming back with nothing.
国内没哪个地方叫这个名字
No place by that name anywhere in this country.
其他国家也没有
Or any other country,for that matter.
行动
Let's go.
那帮兔崽子耍了我们
Son of a bitch set us up.
什么也别说
Not one word.
警员
Officer...
没什么
Nothing.
哦 那孩子挺聪明
Oh,that kid's clever.
这不是地名 是人名
It's not a place,it's a name.
PDA带着吗？
Your PDA,you got it?
是的
Yeah.
查查这个县的人口档案
Bring up the census of this county.
越详细越好
Far back as it goes.
会被人看到的
Somebody's going to see us.
继续挖
Keep digging.
我们会下地狱的
We're gonna go to hell,guys.
我们真的会下地狱的
Swear to God,we're gonna go to hell.
搭把手
Help me out.
你是一只病猫 知道吗?
You are one sick cat,you know that?
你要找什么？
What are you looking for?
我们要去公墓
We got to go to the cemetery.
快
Now.
这本来是我和林肯一个礼拜的衣服
a week's worth of clothes for me and Linc.
相信你们也需要
But,uh,figured you all need just as much help
所以……
as we do,so...
你这么做是出于良心？
You're just doing this out of the goodness of your heart,Fish?
对 阿布鲁奇 良心
That's right,John,the heart.
你还记得什么良心吧
You remember what that is,don't you?
见鬼  这太紧了
Damn,Snowflake,this is tight,man.
就像我说的 脱胎换骨
It's like I said,we got to stop being cons,
变成普通人
start being civilians.
不错
Nice.
裤子短了点 你说呢？
Trousers are a little bit too short,don't you think?
脚砍了就正好 你擅长的
Chop your feet off.You're good at that.
衣服不重要
This jacket ain't exactly the best thing,
知道我的意思吧？
you know what I'm saying?
还想要其它的话自己去买
You want variety,hit Target.
林肯
Linc.
有什么？
What do we got?
钱、护照……
Money,passports...
电话卡
pre-paid phone cards.
阿齐  瑞恩？
Archie Ryan?
看过我的吗？
Did you see mine?
菲尼亚斯 麦克林塔克
Phineas McClintock.
喔 这个？
Whoa. These?
我们车的钥匙
Keys to a car that's waiting for us
几百米之外
a couple hundred yards from here.
为我们2个人还是5个人？
That a two-of-us or five-of-us?
我们2个人
That's a two-of-us.
他们知道吗？
They know?
还不知道
Not yet.
哥们 有人来了
Guy-Guy-Guys,we got company.
哥们 我们该走了
Guys,we got to roll.
他怎么知道的？
How did he know?
我们是普通人 记住
普通人
Civilians.
嘿
Hey.
对不起 现在几点？
I'm sorry,uh. Do you know what time it is?
不知道 抱歉
No,sorry.
我不能出去
I can't go outside
我一露面他们就会干掉我
They'll kill me as soon as I show my face.
你误会了吧
You're wrong about that.
只要你一露面
As soon as you show your face,
就真相大白了
this whole thing is gonna be over.
你可以恢复你的生活 特伦斯
You can have your life back,Terrence.
你保证？
Promise?
我保证
I promise.
你好
Hello.
是我
V,it's me.
我们出来了
We're out.
谢天谢地
Thank God you're okay.
我看新闻了
I saw the news.
你们不能再跑了
You got to stop.
你们得自首
I need you to turn yourself in.
什么？
What?
我找到斯蒂德曼了 我和他在一起 林肯
I found Steadman. I'm with him now,Linc.
他还活着
He's alive.
你会被证明无罪的
You're going to be exonerated.
请进
Come in.
斯蒂德曼...
Steadman...
你在说什么 你找到斯蒂德曼了？
What are you talking about,you found Steadman?
特伦斯 来 我们走
Terrence,come on,let's go.
下午好
Afternoon.
维罗妮卡
Veronica.
警察来了 听着 我要你们留在原地
The police are here. Look,I need you to stay where you are.
我不想失去你
Ma'am. I don't want to lose you.
女士 放下电话
Ma'am,put the phone down.
什么？
What?
斯蒂德曼先生
Mr. Steadman,
后退几步
take a few steps back.
维... 维罗妮卡
Ver... Veronica.
维罗妮卡
Veronica.
哦 天啊
Oh,my God.
维罗妮卡!
Veronica!
你知道我们监控所有打给当地警局的电话
I thought you knew that all calls to the local station are routed through us.
这是联邦区域 还记得吗？
This is federal land,remember?
恩
Mm.
恩 然后你的小玩具
And,uh,as for your little toy here,
是违禁品
it's contraband.
能告诉我  你怎么弄进来的？
You gonna tell us how you got it in there?
来的时候买的
I brought it when I got here.
用来干嘛？
Whatever for?
防身的
To protect myself. Mm.
我们就可以保护你 记住了吗?
That's what we're here for,remember?
有个办法能让事情都顺利
There's a plan to make all of this right.
不到一天 逃犯线索就变少了
In less than a day,the trail has gone cold
现在的追捕变得......
in the pursuit of what are now being called...
好的 行
Yeah,that's fine.
继续跟进 好吗？
Stay on top of it,all right?
他们还在搜索奥斯威戈市
DOC's still doing a sweep of Oswego,
不过这些逃犯好像消失了一样
but the guys have basically vanished.
我不这么想 艾夫斯先生
I wouldn't be so sure about that,Mr. Ives.
我不知道为什么你会这么自信
I don't know how you can be so confident.
他们又没有给你留下地图
It's not like these guys left a map where they're going.
其实他们真的有地图
Actually,that's exactly what they did.
斯科菲尔德身上有所有的计划……
Scofield had the entire thing on his body--
怎么越狱 怎么消失
how to get out of that prison,how to disappear afterward
都有
It's all there
我向你保证只是时间问题
I promise you that it's only a matter of time
我们会知道所有 斯科菲尔德脑袋里的东西
before we know everything that is in Scofield's head--
他计划去哪 怎么去
where he plans to run to,how he plans to get there.
等他到达的时候
So when the time comes that he does get there,
我们就在那里等着他
we'll be waiting for him.